Matt Jones

Winchester, Hampshire
Phone: 07908 197822 | Email: glitchyghost81@protonmail.com
LinkedIn:http://www.linkedin.com/in/matt-jones-zx81
GitHub: https://github.com/Matt-Jones-Developer

Portfolio: https://matt-jones-developer.github.io/i_am_glitchy_react_tailwind_portfolio/

Summary

Talented Front End Web Developer with a background in education and entrepreneurship, a life-long dedication to learning. Effective at combining creativity with problem-solving to develop user-friendly, attractive applications. Highly passionate, motivated and organised with exceptional attention to detail no matter the complexity of the project.

Technical Skills

Languages

HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Javascript ES6+ and Python. React JSX specialist.

Tools & Frameworks

React.js, Next.js, TailwindCSS, Node.js, Sanity.io, Express, jQuery, Bootstrap, Styled-Components, Command Line, GitHub, VSCode, DigitalOcean, Firebase, MongoDB, Inkscape, Photoshop, Construct & Godot game engines, Ableton Live and more.

Projects

Superdrug Edit Magazine - Scalable React.js & TailwindCSS Application |

Server deployment: https://www.editmagazine.co.uk/

Approached by big brand client Superdrug, to create a competition website to coincide with quarterly magazine releases. Presented a detailed proposal covering every step of the build requirements, including a highly scalable end product.

Core Responsibilities:

Designed using Superdrug's style-guide. Submitted a 5 page Figma wireframing mockup for a user first, UX/UI based design. Custom React component & hooks library, and utilised dynamic rendering for cards and forms, all linked to an API. Fully responsive, pixel perfect application, end product deployed to a backend server.

Tools / languages used: React.js, TailwindCSS, Github, Webpack CLI, JSON, Font Awesome, Formspree, API data fetching. Deployment to Digital Ocean server.

WiFinder | The Wifi & Hangout Search Engine

Repo: https://github.com/Matt-Jones-Developer/wi-finder_free_wifi_finder

Live: https://wi-finder.netlify.app/

Collaborative API driven wifi hot-spot finder build, utilising Google Places, Geoaplify API's.

Core Responsibilities:

Lead React Front-End Developer, JavaScript, React, Tailwind, HTML, CSS, UI/UX design.

Tools / languages used: React.js Node.js, Javascript, Tailwind, HTML5, CSS3, Github, CLI, Google Fonts, Font Awesome, email.js, API data fetching.

Experience

Freelance Web Developer
PixelPulseLabs, Winchester, Hampshire, UK

2022 - Present

Core Responsibilities:

Communication, critical thinking, liaising with clients, project management, clean coding.

Key Accomplishments:

- Worked with big name brand Superdrug, to deliver an exciting new application
- Completing project targets before due date using good time management
- Leadership and educational praise from colleagues within a team of 4

Music Technology Facilitation Company CEO/Founder Glitch Music Workshops, Winchester, Hampshire UK

2007 - 2019

Core Responsibilities:

Conceptualised a unique business. Prospected 60+ clients, acquired funding, delivered engaging music workshops. Demonstrated sound communication and presentation skills.

Key Accomplishments:

- Head hunted by client and offered a full time position for dedication to client goals.
- Exceeded targets for engagement by 200%, over 275 successful project outcomes.
- Outperformed and surpassed monthly and annual revenue targets by 45%.

Education

Certificates:

EdX Front End Boot Camp Certificate: Online, UK. Grade: (**A+**) 2022 – 2023 A 24-week intensive program focused on increasing technical programming skills in React.js, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js and UX/UI design principles.

Degree:

Higher National Diploma, Music Technology: A.C.M Guildford, Surrey. 1999 – 2001